[
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Along%20with%20Oxygen%2C%20which%20element%20is%20primarily%20responsible%20for%20the%20sky%20appearing%20blue%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Nitrogen",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Helium",
            "Carbon",
            "Hydrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20the%20colour%20of%20unoxidized%20blood%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Red",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Blue",
            "Purple",
            "Green"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20humerus%2C%20paired%20radius%2C%20and%20ulna%20come%20together%20to%20form%20what%20joint%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Elbow",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Knee",
            "Sholder",
            "Ankle"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "In%20aeronautics%2C%20flaps%20and%20slats%20are%20used%20to%20control%20what%20on%20an%20aircraft%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Lift",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Thrust",
            "Drag",
            "Weight%20"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20of%20these%20stars%20is%20the%20largest%3F",
        "correct_answer": "UY%20Scuti",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "VY%20Canis%20Majoris",
            "Betelgeuse",
            "RW%20Cephei"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20was%20the%20first%20living%20creature%20in%20space%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Fruit%20Flies%20",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Monkey",
            "Dog",
            "Mouse"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20mineral%20has%20the%20lowest%20number%20on%20the%20Mohs%20scale%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Talc",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Quartz",
            "Diamond",
            "Gypsum"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Gannymede%20is%20the%20largest%20moon%20of%20which%20planet%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Jupiter",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Uranus",
            "Neptune",
            "Mars"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "How%20many%20degrees%20Fahrenheit%20is%20100%20degrees%20Celsius%3F%20",
        "correct_answer": "212",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "326",
            "100",
            "451"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "To%20the%20nearest%20minute%2C%20how%20long%20does%20it%20take%20for%20light%20to%20travel%20from%20the%20Sun%20to%20the%20Earth%3F",
        "correct_answer": "8%20Minutes",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "6%20Minutes",
            "2%20Minutes",
            "12%20Minutes"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20chemical%20element%20has%20the%20lowest%20boiling%20point%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Helium",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Hydrogen",
            "Neon",
            "Nitrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20element%20has%20the%20atomic%20number%20of%207%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Nitrogen",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Oxygen",
            "Hydrogen",
            "Neon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Au%20on%20the%20Periodic%20Table%20refers%20to%20which%20element%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Gold",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Silver",
            "Oxygen",
            "Nickel"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "All%20the%20following%20metal%20elements%20are%20liquids%20at%20or%20near%20room%20temperature%20EXCEPT%3A",
        "correct_answer": "Beryllium",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Gallium",
            "Caesium",
            "Mercury"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20Axiom%20of%20Preventive%20Medicine%20states%20that%20people%20with%20___%20risk%20for%20a%20disease%20should%20be%20screened%20and%20we%20should%20treat%20___%20of%20those%20people.",
        "correct_answer": "low%2C%20all",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "low%2C%20some",
            "high%2C%20all",
            "high%2C%20some"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "How%20many%20officially%20recognized%20dwarf%20planets%20in%20the%20solar%20system%20are%20named%20after%20Polynesian%20deities%3F",
        "correct_answer": "2",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20psychological%20term%20refers%20to%20the%20stress%20of%20holding%20contrasting%20beliefs%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Cognitive%20Dissonance",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Flip-Flop%20Syndrome",
            "Split-Brain",
            "Blind%20Sight"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20%22Tibia%22%20is%20found%20in%20which%20part%20of%20the%20body%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Leg",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Arm",
            "Hand",
            "Head"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Who%20developed%20the%20first%20successful%20polio%20vaccine%20in%20the%201950s%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Jonas%20Salk",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "John%20F.%20Enders",
            "Thomas%20Weller",
            "Frederick%20Robbins"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20the%20chemical%20formula%20for%20ammonia%3F",
        "correct_answer": "NH3",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "CO2",
            "NO3",
            "CH4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Where%20did%20the%20dog%20breed%20%22Chihuahua%22%20originate%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Mexico",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "France",
            "Spain",
            "Russia"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20polymer%20is%20used%20to%20make%20CDs%2C%20safety%20goggles%20and%20riot%20shields%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Polycarbonate",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Rubber",
            "Nylon",
            "Bakelite"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20medical%20condition%20osteoporosis%20affects%20which%20part%20of%20the%20body%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Bones",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Skin",
            "Brain",
            "Heart"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20the%20atomic%20number%20of%20the%20element%20Strontium%3F",
        "correct_answer": "38",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "73",
            "47",
            "11"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20of%20these%20is%20NOT%20a%20part%20of%20the%20structure%20of%20a%20typical%20neuron%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Islets%20of%20Langerhans",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Node%20of%20Ranvier",
            "Schwann%20cell",
            "Myelin%20sheath"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20part%20of%20the%20body%20does%20glaucoma%20affect%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Eyes",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Throat",
            "Stomach",
            "Blood"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20term%20is%20best%20associated%20with%20Sigmund%20Freud%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Psychoanalysis",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Cognitive-Behavioral%20Therapy",
            "Theory%20of%20Gravity",
            "Dialectical%20Behavior%20Therapy"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20one%20of%20these%20scientists%20conducted%20the%20Gold%20Foil%20Experiment%20which%20concluded%20that%20atoms%20are%20mostly%20made%20of%20empty%20space%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Ernest%20Rutherford",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Joseph%20John%20Thomson",
            "Archimedes",
            "Niels%20Henrik%20David%20Bohr"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "After%20which%20Danish%20city%20is%20the%2072th%20element%20on%20the%20periodic%20table%20named%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Copenhagen",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Odense",
            "Herning",
            "Skagen"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20does%20the%20yellow%20diamond%20on%20the%20NFPA%20704%20fire%20diamond%20represent%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Reactivity",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Health",
            "Flammability",
            "Radioactivity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20human%20right%20lung%20has%20how%20many%20lobes%3F",
        "correct_answer": "3",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "4",
            "2",
            "1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Myopia%20is%20the%20scientific%20term%20for%20which%20condition%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Shortsightedness",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Farsightedness",
            "Double%20Vision",
            "Clouded%20Vision"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "In%20Chemistry%2C%20how%20many%20isomers%20does%20Butanol%20%28C4H9OH%29%20have%3F",
        "correct_answer": "4",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "3",
            "5",
            "6"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20stage%20of%20development%20do%20the%20majority%20of%20eukaryotic%20cells%20remain%20in%20for%20most%20of%20their%20life%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Interphase",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Prophase",
            "Stasis",
            "Telophase"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "At%20what%20temperature%20does%20water%20boil%3F",
        "correct_answer": "212%C2%B0F",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "200%C2%B0F",
            "181%C2%B0F",
            "178%C2%B0F"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20of%20these%20elements%20on%20the%20Periodic%20Table%20is%20a%20Noble%20Gas%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Neon",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Potassium",
            "Iodine",
            "Colbalt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Deuterium%20is%20an%20isotope%20of%20which%20element%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Hydrogen",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Nitrogen",
            "Helium",
            "Neon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "A%20positron%20is%20an%20antiparticle%20of%20a%20what%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Electron",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Neutron",
            "Proton",
            "Photon"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Who%20made%20the%20discovery%20of%20X-rays%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Wilhelm%20Conrad%20R%C3%B6ntgen",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Thomas%20Alva%20Edison",
            "James%20Watt",
            "Albert%20Einstein"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "About%20how%20old%20is%20Earth%3F",
        "correct_answer": "4.5%20Billion%20Years",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "3.5%20Billion%20Years",
            "2.5%20Billion%20Years",
            "5.5%20Billion%20Years"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20radiation%20measured%20in%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Gray%20",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Watt",
            "Decibel",
            "Kelvin"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20the%20unit%20of%20electrical%20capacitance%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Farad",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Gauss",
            "Henry",
            "Watt"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20desert%20is%20the%20only%20desert%20in%20the%20world%20where%20the%20%22Saguaro%22%20cactus%20grows%20indigenously%3F",
        "correct_answer": "The%20Sonoran%20Desert",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "The%20Gobi%20Desert",
            "The%20Yuma%20Desert",
            "The%20Arabian%20Desert"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "In%20Psychology%2C%20which%20need%20appears%20highest%20in%20the%20%22Maslow%27s%20hierarchy%20of%20needs%22%20pyramid%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Esteem",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Love",
            "Safety",
            "Physiological"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20are%20human%20nails%20made%20of%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Keratin",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Bone",
            "Chitin",
            "Calcium"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "The%20Sun%20consists%20of%20mostly%20which%20two%20elements%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Hydrogen%20%26%20Helium",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Hydrogen%20%26%20Nitrogen",
            "Carbon%20%26%20Nitrogen",
            "Carbon%20%26%20Helium"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20is%20the%20largest%20living%20organism%20currently%20known%20to%20man%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Honey%20Fungus",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Blue%20Whale",
            "Redwood%20Tree",
            "The%20Coral%20Reef"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "On%20which%20mission%20did%20the%20Space%20Shuttle%20Columbia%20break%20up%20upon%20re-entry%3F",
        "correct_answer": "STS-107",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "STS-51-L",
            "STS-61-C",
            "STS-109"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "What%20part%20of%20the%20brain%20takes%20its%20name%20from%20the%20Greek%20for%20seahorse%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Hippocampus",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Cerebellum",
            "Thalamus",
            "Amygdala"
        ]
    },
    {
        "category": "Science%20%26%20Nature",
        "type": "multiple",
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "Which%20planet%20did%20the%20%22Viking%201%22%20spacecraft%20send%20surface%20images%20of%2C%20starting%20in%201976%3F",
        "correct_answer": "Mars",
        "incorrect_answers": [
            "Saturn",
            "Jupiter",
            "Venus"
        ]
    }
]